# Cihan CINAR

**TECHNICAL EXPERT - FULLSTACK** 

## **PROFILE**

I am a Full Stack Technical Expert, with over 6 years of experience and always eager to learn something new.

I am currently employed at SQLI Suisse as a Technical Expert, where I am working in agile methodology on various projects, with high expectations and tight deadlines. Specialized in Java, I am actively working on software design, architecture and IaaS, CaaS deployment. However I am adaptable and I enjoy learning new technologies.

Pedagogue and passionate about my work, I participate in university or inhouse technical trainings. I actively follow web conferences such as Devoxx to keep me informed of the latest technologies and trends and I try to implement new approaches that I think are promising. The technical challenge is at the heart of my activity and as I enjoy taking initiatives I participated for few years at Labs as a day a week for R&D.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# SQLI

## **Technical Lead - Digital Innovation (Givaudan)**

#### n 02/2022 - Present

Design and development of Givaudan innovation solution based on fragrance and flavour. I lead the Tableau software overlay product which help internal business to use full capacity of Tableau through an Angular pre build app with advanced filter management and board builder.

Java 11, SpringBoot (Security, MVC, Data, WebFlux), Maven, Angular 13, Openshift, Gitlab-ci, Docker, Jira, Tableau

# equensWorldline

## **Architect - Identity Provider (NS&I)**

## **1** 04/2021 - 01/2022

Design and development of the NSI identification solution. Implementation of strong authentication based on OpenBanking solution for web and mobile channels. Helped NSI technical teams to interconnect their solutions with the new authentication solution. I carried out the performance tests as well as the patches. I set up the whole DevOps part. And I lead technically a team of 6 developers.

Keycloak, Apigee, Drupal Java 11, SpringBoot (Security, MVC, Data, WebFlux), Maven, Angular 9, Openshift, Helm, Gitlab-ci, Docker, Jira

### **Architect - OpenBanking**

#### **1** 06/2020 - 03/2021

Design and development of a generic consent, authorization and authentication solution using the OPENID connect protocol through RH SSO and Apigee. I build the architecture of the identity provider platform for the largest English bank.

I am working with our TPP Reach solutions to design and respond to pre-sales, and I'm studying the implementation of a solution like Google login for banks.

I am working on the design of a green banking solution with the implementation of carbon footprint calculation for banking transactions.

Keycloak, Apigee, Drupal

Java 11, SpringBoot (Security, MVC, Data, WebFlux), Maven, Angular 9, Openshift, Helm, Gitlab-ci, Docker, Jira

### Technical Lead - Chatbot (McDonald's)

#### **3** 09/2019 - 06/2020

Design and development of a chatbot solution using channels such as Alexa, Google Home, Messenger, Rest API, WebSocket, using for intention recognition our RASA-based NLP engine coupled with an approaching search and disambiguation engine.

Implementation of an administration tool for corpus management and administration of the bot and discussions on the different channels.

Kotlin, SpringBoot (Security, MVC, Data), Maven, Angular 9, Openshift, Helm, Gitlab-ci, Docker, Jira

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Lead Developer - PSD2 (Commerzbank, Orange bank, .. 25 banks)

**10/2018 - 09/2019** 

Design, development and operation of the Digital Banking product line for the implementation of the PSD2 standard based on the BerlinGroup and OpenBanking standards, through the Apigee API manager. I carried out the performance tests as well as the patches. I set up the whole DevOps part. And I lead technically a team of 10 developers.

Java, SpringBoot (Cloud, Security, Data, MVC), Docker, Ember, Kafka, Drupal, Maven, Node, TLS

## **Software Engineer - Digital Signature (AG2R La Mondiale)**

**3**03/2016 - 10/2018

- Design, development and operation of underwriting applications of dematerialized contracts for various banking and insurance customers, implementing the electronic signature.

Java, SpringBoot (XML, Boot, MVC, Data), AngularJs, REST et SOAP, Maven, TLS

- Design, development and operation of a digital banking product for the implementation of API connector between third parties and bank for all banking transactions.

Java, JEE, Spring (Cloud), Ember, REST, Maven, Node, TLS

# <u>Université Claude Bernard Lyon 1</u>

#### Part-time teacher

**1**0/2018 - 12/2018 & **1**0/2019 - 12/2019

Teacher (practical work) for web application design courses for 1st year of master computer science of the university Lyon 1.

The general theme is "web-oriented" design using software engineering patterns (MVC, REST, asynchronous, framework, templating.). Technically, it involves programming in Java on the server side (servlet, JSP, Spring) and in JS on the client side (AJAX, jQuery).

# LIRIS - CNRS (Research Laboratory in computer science)

# Internship

**1** 05/2015 - 08/2015

Development of a graph storage engine for a distributed system.

Multi-segment partition loading, latices generation, compression and code optimization with float loading.

Work on the Petasky project, on the fragmentation and data storage part, in C++, JAVA, SPARQL and RDF.

## CONTACT

- **\** +33 6 43 27 96 40
- □ cihancnr@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/cihancinar
- github.com/cihancinar
- O cihancinar.github.io/
- 6 rue du Beulet, Annemasse 74100 FRANCE

## LANGUAGE

English

French

Turkish

## LAST TRAINING

- Kafka Developer Skils
- Blockchain
- Openshift
- Kotlin
- Docker

## **EDUCATION**

Université Claude Bernard Lyon 1 9 France, Lyon

Master of Information Technology and Web in Computer Science

**2014 - 2016** 

IUT Informatique Dijon Prance, Dijon

**University of Computer Science** 

**2011 – 2013** 

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

## **Programmation:**

Software Development:

Java, Kotlin, JEE, Spring (Cloud, Boot, MVC, Data, Security), Docker, Node.JS, Maven *Web Development:* 

HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript (Angular, EmberJS), jQuery

# **Continus integration:**

Jenkins, Gitlab (CI), Openshift, Helm

## **Project management:**

Agile (Scrum Kanban), Jira, Confluence

# **Database Technologies:**

SQL, MySQL, MongoDB

### **Tools:**

Keycloak, Apigee, Kafka, ELK